<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googlesheetsconnector.png" type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Google Sheets Interactive Service Provider</name>
	<shortDescription>Create a Google Sheets connection.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Create a Google Sheets connection using interactive authentication, via pop-up.
			<p>
			Authentication happens in the dialog.
			By default, received credentials will be stored in the node.
			However, a custom credential location can be set in the dialog.
			A custom credential location is useful for sharing the credentials via a KNIME server or for exposing the user credentials.
			</p>
			<p>
			After choosing the credential location, one must authenticate using the (Re-)Authentication button. 
			A pop-up will appear that asks the user to grant access to Google Sheets and Google Drive. 
			If you have already authenticated, the (Re-)Authentication will test the stored credentials in the selected location. 
			When choosing and confirming the custom credentials the default credentials will be forgotten, they can also manually be forgotten using the corresponding button.
			</p>
			<p>
			Access can be revoked at any time by visiting <a href="https://myaccount.google.com/permissions">myaccount.google.com/permissions</a>
			</p>
			<p>
			For details see: <a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsAccounts">developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsAccounts</a>.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Credential Location">
		Where the credentials received during authentication will be stored.
			<br/>
			<b>Default</b>
			<p>
			Credentials will be stored in the node instance.
			<br/>
			<b>Forget Default Credentials</b>
			<br/>
			This button will remove the credentials which are stored as part of the node instance.
			</p>
			<b>Custom</b>
			<p>
			<b>User id</b>
			<br/>
			A user id under which the tokens should be saved. 
			Multiple users' credentials can be stored in the same location.
			<br/>
			<b>Select Directory</b>
			<br/>
			The directory to which the credentials should be saved.
			</p>
		</option>
		<option name="(Re-)Authentication">
		This button will open a dialog to authenticate with Google Services. 
		If you are already authenticated, it will test the stored credentials in the selected location.
		</option>
		
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Google Sheets Connection">A connection that can be used to
			access Google Sheets.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
