<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googlesheets.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Google Sheets Updater</name>
	<shortDescription>This node updates values in an existing sheet.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node writes the input data table to an existing Google sheet.
			
			It can overwrite some or all of the content of a sheet or append to the content of a sheet.
			
			If only part of the content of a sheet is to be overwritten, the relevant range can be specified in A1 notation.
			The size of the input table must not exceed the size of the selected range, otherwise execution will fail.
		</intro>
		<option name="Spreadsheet">
			The spreadsheet can be selected from the spreadsheets available on Google Drive.
			You can see the unique spreadsheet ID by hovering over the name.
		</option>
		<option name="Select...">
			Opens a dialog which lists the available spreadsheets from google drive. 
			In the dialog you can see the unique spreadsheet ID by hovering over the names.
		</option>
		<option name="Open in Browser...">
			Opens the selected spreadsheet in the browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Sheet">
			The sheet from the spreadsheet that should be updated. Available sheets can be selected from the drop-down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="Select First Sheet">
			When selected, the first sheet of the spreadsheet will be updated instead of the one selected from the drop-down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="Range">
			Here the range that should be updated from the sheet can be specified in A1 notation. (E.g. "A1:G20")
		</option>
		<option name="Add column header">
			Here you determine whether the column names should be written in the first row.
		</option>
		<option name="Add row header">
			Here you determine whether the row ID's should be written in the first column.
		</option>
		<option name="For missing values write">
		By selecting this option, you can specify a string you want to substitute for missing values.
		If the option is left unchecked, the cells with missing values remain empty.
		</option>
		<option name="Write raw (do not parse numbers, dates, hyperlinks, etc.)">
			Values are written into the spreadsheet as-is (&quot;raw&quot;), i.e. they will <i>not</i> be parsed. 
			Uncheck the option, if values should be written into the spreadsheet as if they were entered via the Google 
			Sheets website. 
			If unchecked, numbers will stay as numbers, but other strings may be converted to numbers, dates, etc. 
			following the same rules that are applied when entering text into a cell via the Google Sheets website.
			For example, strings like <tt>=hyperlink("example.com", "example")</tt> will be parsed to hyperlinks
			if this option is unchecked.
		</option>
		<option name="Append to sheet">
		When this option is selected, the data table content will be appended to the selected sheet.
		</option>
		<option name="Clear sheet before writing">
		When this option is selected, the sheet or the selected range of the sheet will be cleared before writing. This deletes the content in the specified sheet/range.
		</option>
		<option name="Open spreadsheet after execution">
		Opens the spreadsheet after it has been written successfully. 
		The spreadsheet will be opened in the systems's default browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Exclude/Include columns">
			Select the columns that will be written to the sheet file. 
			If the columns in the input table change, they will automatically be excluded.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Google Sheets Connection">A Google Sheets connection.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Buffered data table">Table to be written to a Google sheet</inPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>Spreadsheet</keyword>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>
