<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googlesheets.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Google Sheet Updater</name>
	<shortDescription>Updates values in an existing sheet.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node writes the input data table to an existing google sheet.
			
			The data table's content can either overwrite the sheets existing content or be
			appended at the end of the existing table.
			
			What is being overwritten depends on the input table's size.
			
			Additionally the data table content can be written to a specific range, given in A1 notation.
			If the input table size does not correspond to the size of the given A1 notation execution will fail.
		</intro>
		<option name="Spreadsheet">
			The spreadsheet can be selected from available spreadsheets in google drive.
		</option>
		<option name="Select...">
			Opens a dialog which lists the available spreadsheets from google drive.
		</option>
		<option name="Open">
			Opens the selected spreadsheet in the browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Sheet">
			The sheet from the spreadsheet that should be read. Available sheets can be selected from the drop down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="Select First Sheet">
			When selected, the first sheet of the spreadsheet will be read instead of the one selected from the drop down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="Range">
			A specific range to which the data table content should be written can be given in A1 notation. (E.g. "A1:G20")
		</option>
		<option name="Add column header">
			Whether the column names should be written in the first row.
		</option>
		<option name="Add row header">
			Whether the row ids should be written in the first column.
		</option>
		<option name="For missing values write">
		Enter a pattern that is set for missing data values. 
		If not specified, the corresponding cell of the sheet stays empty.
		</option>
		<option name="Append to sheet">
		When this option is selected, the data table content will be appended to the end of the selected sheet.
		</option>
		<option name="Clear sheet before writing">
		When this option is selected the sheet, or the selected range of the sheet will be cleared before writing. This deletes the content in the specified sheet/range.
		</option>
		<option name="Open spreadsheet after execution">
		Opens the spreadsheet after it has been successfully written. 
		The spreadsheet will be opened in the systems's default browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Exclude/Include columns">
			Select the columns that will be written to the sheet file. 
			If the columns in the input table should change, they will automatically be excluded.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Google Sheets Connection">A Google Sheets connection.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Buffered data table">Table to be written to a google sheet</inPort>
		<outPort name="Table" index="0">Table containing the spreadsheet name, sheet name and spreadsheet ID.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
