<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googlesheets.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Google Sheets Writer</name>
	<shortDescription>This node writes the input data table to a new Google Sheets spreadsheet.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node writes the input data table to a new Google Sheets spreadsheet.
			<p>
			If you want to overwrite or append data to an existing sheet, you cannot use the Google Sheets Writer node;
			you must use the Google Sheets Updater node.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Spreadsheet name">
			The name of the spreadsheet to be created.
		</option>
		<option name="Sheet name">
			The name of the sheet to which the table should be written.
		</option>
		<option name="Add column header">
			Here you determine whether the column names should be written in the first row.
		</option>
		<option name="Add row header">
			Here you determine whether the row ID's should be written in the first column.
		</option>
		<option name="For missing values write">
		By selecting this option, you can specify a string you want to substitute for missing values.
		If the option is left unchecked, the cells with missing values remain empty.
		</option>
		<option name="Write raw (do not parse numbers, dates, hyperlinks, etc.)">
			Values are written into the spreadsheet as-is (&quot;raw&quot;), i.e. they will <i>not</i> be parsed. 
			Uncheck the option, if values should be written into the spreadsheet as if they were entered via the Google 
			Sheets website. 
			If unchecked, numbers will stay as numbers, but other strings may be converted to numbers, dates, etc. 
			following the same rules that are applied when entering text into a cell via the Google Sheets website.
			For example, strings like <tt>=hyperlink("example.com", "example")</tt> will be parsed to hyperlinks
			if this option is unchecked.
		</option>
		<option name="Open spreadsheet after execution">
		Opens the spreadsheet after it has been written successfully. 
		The spreadsheet will be opened in the systems's default browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Exclude/Include columns">
			Select the columns that will be written to the sheet file. 
			If the columns in the input table change, they will automatically be excluded.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Google Sheets Connection">A Google Sheets connection.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Buffered data table">Table to be written to a google sheet</inPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>Spreadsheet</keyword>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>
