<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googleapiconnector.png"
		type="Source" 
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd"
		deprecated="true" >
	<name>Google Authenticator (Deprecated)</name>
	<shortDescription>Authenticates to Google Services</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This nodes authenticates to Google services specified in the node settings.
			<p>
			Authentication happens in the configuration window.
			By default, credentials are stored in memory.
			Custom credentials can be set in the configuration window.
			A custom credential location is useful for sharing the credentials via a KNIME Server or for exposing the user credentials.
			</p>
			<p>
			After choosing the credential location, one must authenticate using the "Authenticate" button. 
			A pop-up will appear that asks the user to grant access to the selected scopes. 
			If you have already authenticated, the "Authenticate" will test the stored credentials in the selected location. 
			Credentials can be manually deleted by clicking on the "Clear Selected Credentials" button.
			</p>
			<p>
			Access can be revoked at any time by visiting <a href="https://myaccount.google.com/permissions">myaccount.google.com/permissions</a>
			</p>
			<p>
			For details see: <a href="https://developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsAccounts">developers.google.com/analytics/resources/concepts/gaConceptsAccounts</a>.
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Authenticate">
		Clicking on this button will open a dialog for authenticating with Google services. 
		If you are already authenticated, it will verify the stored credentials in the selected location.
		<br/>
		<b>Status</b>
		<p>
		Describes the state of the authentication.
		</p>
		</option>
		<option name="Credential Location">
		This option determines where the credentials received during authentication will be stored.
			<br/>
			<b>Memory</b>
			<p>
			The authentication credentials will be kept in memory. They are discarded when exiting KNIME.
			<br/>
			</p>
			<b>Custom</b>
			<p>
			The authentication credentials will be saved in separate file in the given directory.
			<br/>
			<b>Select Directory</b>
			<br/>
			The directory to which the credentials should be saved.
			</p>
			<b>Node</b>
			<p>
			The authentication credentials will be saved in the node settings.
			<br/>
			</p>
		</option>
		<option name="Scopes">
			Scopes used to authenticate with Google. These can be selected according to the nodes that should be used
			with the Google connection.
			<br/>
			<b>All scopes</b>
			<p>
			Selects all scopes, so the credentials can be used with all available Google Connection nodes.
			</p>
		</option>
		
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<outPort index="0" name="Google Service Connection">A connection that can be used to
			access various Google services.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
