<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googlesheets.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Google Sheets Appender</name>
	<shortDescription>Appends a new sheet to an existing spreadsheet in Google Sheets.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Writes the input table to a new sheet of an existing spreadsheet in Google Sheets.
		</intro>
		<option name="Spreadsheet">
			The spreadsheet can be selected from the spreadsheets available on Google Drive.
			You can see the unique spreadsheet ID by hovering over the name.
		</option>
		<option name="Select...">
			Opens a dialog which lists the available spreadsheets from google drive. 
			In the dialog you can see the unique spreadsheet ID by hovering over the names.
		</option>
		<option name="Open in Browser...">
			Opens the selected spreadsheet in the browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Sheet name">
			The name of the sheet to which the table should be written.
		</option>
		<option name="Add column header">
			Here you determine whether the column names should be written in the first row.
		</option>
		<option name="Add row header">
			Here you determine whether the row ID's should be written in the first column.
		</option>
		<option name="For missing values write">
		By selecting this option, you can specify a string you want to substitute for missing values.
		If the option is left unchecked, the cells with missing values remain empty.
		</option>
		<option name="Write raw">
			Values are written into the spreadsheet as-is (&quot;raw&quot;). Uncheck the option, if values should be 
			written as if they were entered via the Google Sheets website.
		</option>
		<option name="Create unique sheet name">
		The node will create a unique sheet name based on the given sheet name.
		(Example: Should 'SheetOne' already exist, the unique sheet name will be 'SheetOne (#1)')
		</option>
		<option name="Open spreadsheet after execution">
		Opens the spreadsheet after it has been written successfully. 
		The spreadsheet will be opened in the systems's default browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Exclude/Include columns">
			Select the columns that will be written to the sheet file. 
			If the columns in the input table change, they will automatically be excluded.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Google Sheets Connection">A Google Sheets connection.</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Buffered data table">Table to be written to a Google sheet</inPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>Spreadsheet</keyword>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>
