<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./file_system_connector.png"
		type="Source"
		xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1"
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
    <name>Google Cloud Storage Connector (Labs)</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Connects to Google Cloud Storage in order to read/write files in downstream nodes.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>This node connects to Google Cloud Storage. The resulting output port allows downstream nodes to access
            the Google Cloud Storage data of a <i>project</i> as a file system, e.g. to read or write files and folders,
            or to perform other file system operations (browse/list files, copy, move, ...).
            </p>
            
            <p><b>Path syntax:</b> Paths for Google Cloud Storage are specified with a UNIX-like syntax, /mybucket/myfolder/myfile. An absolute
            for Google Cloud Storage consists of:
                <ol>
                    <li>A leading slash ("/").</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of a bucket ("mybucket" in the above example), followed by a slash.</li>
                    <li>Followed by the name of an object within the bucket ("myfolder/myfile" in the above example).</li>
                </ol>
            </p>
            
            <p>Please note that for authentication purposes, this node requires the "Google Authentication (API key)" node to be connected to its input port.</p>
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Settings">
	        <option name="Project ID">
	            Specifies the <a href="https://cloud.google.com/storage/docs/key-terms#projects">project</a> to which the Cloud Storage data belongs.
	            See <a href="https://cloud.google.com/resource-manager/docs/creating-managing-projects#identifying_projects">Google Cloud Documentation</a> for more informations.
	        </option>
	        <option name="Working directory">
	            Specifies the <i>working directory</i> using the path syntax explained above. The working directory must be specified as an absolute path. A working directory allows downstream
	            nodes to access files/folders using <i>relative</i> paths, i.e. paths that do not have a leading slash. If not specified, the default working directory
	            is "/".
	        </option>
	        <option name="Normalize paths">
	            Determines if the path normalization should be applied. Path normalization eliminates redundant components of a path like, e.g. /a/../b/./c" can be normalized to "/b/c".
	            When these redundant components like "../" or "." are part of an existing object, then normalization must be deactivated in order to access them properly.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced">
	        <option name="Connection timeout in seconds">
	            Timeout in seconds to establish a connection or 0 for an infinite timeout. 
	        </option>
	        <option name="Read timeout in seconds">
	            Timeout in seconds to read data from an established connection or 0 for an infinite timeout.
	        </option>
        </tab>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Google API Connection">
            The Google Service Connection that carries authentication credentials. Please note that currently only the "Google Authentication (API key)" node
            can be connected to this port. 
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Google Cloud Storage File System Connection">
            Google Cloud Storage File System Connection
        </outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
