<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./googlesheets.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v4.1" 
		xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v4.1 http://knime.org/node/v4.1.xsd">
	<name>Google Sheets Reader</name>
	<shortDescription>Read tables from Google Sheets.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node reads a tab ("sheet") of a Google spreadsheet. The spreadsheet can be selected from the spreadsheets available on Google Drive.
			Optionally, a specific range can be read from the sheet.  The range must be entered in A1 notation (E.g. "A1:G10").
			
			<p>
				For more information about A1 notation visit: 
				<a href="https://developers.google.com/sheets/api/guides/concepts#a1_notation">
				developers.google.com/sheets/api/guides/concepts#a1_notation</a>
			</p>
		</intro>
		<option name="Spreadsheet">
			The spreadsheet can be selected from the spreadsheets available on Google Drive.
			You can see the unique spreadsheet ID by hovering over the name.
		</option>
		<option name="Select...">
			Opens a dialog which lists the available spreadsheets from google drive. 
			In the dialog you can see the unique spreadsheet ID by hovering over the names.
		</option>
		<option name="Open in Browser...">
			Opens the selected spreadsheet in the browser.
		</option>
		<option name="Sheet">
			The sheet from the spreadsheet that should be read. Available sheets can be selected from the drop-down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="Select First Sheet">
			When selected, the first sheet of the spreadsheet will be read instead of the one selected from the drop-down menu.
		</option>
		<option name="Range">
			Here the range that should be read from the sheet can be specified in A1 notation. (E.g. "A1:G20")
		</option>
		<option name="Read column name">
			Here you can specify whether the first row of the sheet should be read as column names.
		</option>
		<option name="Read row id">
			Here you can specify whether the first column of the sheet should be read as row ID's.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Google Sheets Connection">A Google Sheets Connection.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Buffered Data Table" index="0">The retrieved sheet.</outPort>
	</ports>
	<keywords>
		<keyword>Spreadsheet</keyword>
	</keywords>
</knimeNode>
